Guide to the Susan Christopherson papers, circa 1983-2016.
Christopherson, Susan papers,
- Series I. Course materials pedagogy
  - Assignments, Exercises, Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Discussion questions for CRP 448/548
  - Exams, Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    CRP 448/548 exams
  - Measuring Poverty-Background, Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Materials relating this topic for CRP 448/548
  - Poverty-Causes, Relation to Welfare, Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Materials relating this topic for CRP 448/548 including overhead
  - Poverty Spatially, Undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Racism and Federalism (Wk 10/11), Undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Materials relating this topic for CRP 448/548 including set of overheads for lecture and discussion question as well as (among other things) draft of paper by Susan Meiklejohn
  - Race, Class, Affirmative Action and Social Policy, Undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Materials relating this topic for CRP 448/548 including notes for course lectures
  - Wealth and Income, Undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Lecture Notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Lecture notes for CRP 448/548
  - Education, Schools, Opportunity, Undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Affirmative Action, Undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Generational Inequality, Undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Privatization, Undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Devolution, Undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Social Policy Immigration, Undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Welfare and Citizenship Rights, Undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Health Care/The Welfare State, Undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Civic Technologies, 2014 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    Notes and correspondence regarding the teaching of technology in planning courses. Includes notes from converstation with Kieran Doneghy and e-mail from Tatiana Mooreira De Souza at University College London inviting SMC to visit the Urban Skills Portal website set up by Professor Matthew Carmona.
  - Professional Development Oriented Courses, 2015-03-05 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    A teaching plan for an "Elevator Pitch" workshop for CRP students (with Tom Hambury) along with notes on "design thinking" and guidelines for writing a policy brief
  - State EconomyDevelopment Talk, Undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - CRP 417/517 Material, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - New Regionalism Critique Learning, Undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - CRP 417/517 Material, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - CRP Writing Course, 2016-02-22 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Articles for 417/517, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - CRP 417/517 Midterm, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - CRP 417/517 Material, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - CRP 417/517 Paper 1, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - CRP 4170/5170 Lecture Notes, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - CRP 4170/5170 Readings, Undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Spring 5170 Course, 2014 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Policy Brief Assignment, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - CRP 5074 Syllabus, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Urban theory/planning, Undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Financialization reading, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Economic implications of Marcellus shale natural gas development, 2011-05-09 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Urban Theory, Spring 2011 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Theory Seminar, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Syllabus CRP 417/517, Undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - CRP 448/635, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Economic development cities, Undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Housing policy debate, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Road maps and brochures, Undated (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Course slides, 1979; ZD-80-81 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Series II. Research
  - Canal Corridor Initiative Publications, 1999-2001 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Includes reports and discs relating to the evaluation of the Canal Corridor Initiative
  - Canal Corridor Initiative, 1999-2001 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Includes rmaterials relating to the evaluation of the Canal Corridor Initiative
  - Rochester-Interview Notes 2000, 2000-03-14 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Includes a summary of various interviews conducted in Rochester
  - Rochester Photonics, 2000-2002; CD-3849-3852 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Includes research notes, interview transcripts, conference-related material, proposal to U.S. Department of Labor, etc.
  - Temp. Employment/Optics, 2000-2002 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Includes various prepub draft of Peck/Theodore 2002 article on temp workers with SMC comments, and a number of temp work-related documents including thoughts on their progress understanding temp work in Rochester
  - Photonics Cluster, Undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Material related to photonics interviews
  - Rochester High Falls Article, 2003-04-06 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Article about High Falls project in which SMC is quoted
  - Rochester Workshop Reports, 2000-2001 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Contains student reports about Rochester and interview transcripts generated as part of CRP Workshops in Economic Development Policy
  - Rochester Survey Master and Design, 2002-06-2003 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Also contains summary of preliminary results
  - Rochester Report Release Plans, 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Typology Materials Rochester Photonics Research, 2001-2003 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    Includes some analysis a few questionaires and related materials
  - Rochester Phone Survey Responses, 2002-06 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Rochester Community Audit Documents, Proposals, 2000-01-2000-12 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Sample Workforce Reports, Undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Notes on a lecture by Fred Dedrick, other notes--I threw out a Center on Policy Initiatives report on San Diego, and another on Philadelphia that were published elsewhere
  - Clark Ideas, Undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Ideas related to studying creativity as per her endowed professorship
  - Materials for U/Community Report, Undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Related to arts and community research
  - Toolbox Papers, Undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Drafts of papers/CARDI report on universities and creative local economies-two with Suzanne Loker and Susan Monagan
  - Creative Campus Project, 2006-11-01 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Just one sheet-a list of people on a panel
  - Hatch--To Do, 2004-2005 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    Contains materials relating to cultural activities surveys
  - Ithaca Forward Project, 2007-2008 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Contains notes and materials relating to the Ithaca Forward economic development initiative (to keep young people in Tompkins County)
  - Notes for Rochester Paper, Undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
    6 pages of notes that are attached to "Chapter Four" with the source of that chapter unknown.
  - CRP Cornell Common Good Planning Council 1999 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Report and Drafts entitled The Rochester Metropolitan Economy: An Initial Assessment, by SMC, Pierre Clavel, and Joseph Mathews
  - Rochester Community Audit Dept. of Labor Grant Info, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    Contains proposal and notification of award
  - Outline Commenwealth Article, Undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
    Contains document entitled "Outline for Commonwealth Article on Urban Poverty and "Third Tier" Cities in New England--author unknown
  - Memo Burchell, Joan 8/01, 2001-08 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    Memo from Joan Burchell and Barbara Baran to Community Audit Demonstration Project Grantees with a handwritten note from SMC reading "Contact BB about Temp survey suggestions)
  - Christopherson Letter to James Winston, Undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
    Letter to the Coordinator of the Monroe County Manufacturing Partnership.
  - Christopherson Meeting Notes 4/12/01, 2001-04-12 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    Appears to be notes relating to meeting preparing proposal for Annie E. Casey Foundation (see also Correspondence Box 1 Folder 4)
  - Clavel, Pierre Email 1/26/99, 1/18/00, Fall 1999 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    Two notes regarding the Syracuse, then Rochester research project
  - Rochester Databases, 2002-08-05 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    3 1/4" disc containing 3 datebase files for Rochester Project
  - Wal-Mart Related Articles, Undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
    From file box labeled: Wal-Mart (boxed 1/07)--academic and popular press articles about Wal-Mart and box stores, most with underlining
  - Quality Comm/Hatch/Ithaca CC Project, Undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
    Notes and documents relating to festival and creative community projects
  - Upstate Research, Undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
    Includes a spreadsheet on the integration of NYS higher ed institutions with creative economy (by institution), some notes, a copy of the draft 2004 Empire State Poll
  - Crevoisier, O, Undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
    An article by Crevoisier, annotated, and two pages of hand-written notes
  - Christopherson, S. and Clark, J., Undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
    Draft outline precis of book, along with SMC notes on the same
  - Wal-Mart Related Articles, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    From file box labeled: Wal-Mart (boxed 1/07)--academic and popular press articles about Wal-Mart and box stores, most with underlining, many sent to her by various people
  - Wal-Mart Materials, Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    From file box labeled: Wal-Mart (boxed 1/07)--Includes articles, search keywords and results, and a draft of a piece of an article
  - Logistics Notes, Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
    From file box labeled: Wal-Mart (boxed 1/07)--Includes handwritten notes about what Wal-Mart, logistics, and the company's failure in Germany
  - Wal-Mart Notes, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    includes a few notes and e-mails
  - Braun Wal-Mart Paper, 2004-04-02-2005-02-11 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    From file box labeled: Wal-Mart (boxed 1/07)--Three pieces of correspondence from Stanley Brunn, who was editing a book entitled 'Wal-Mart World,' in which SMC would have a chapter entitled "The Myth of Wal-Martization: Retail Globalization and Local Competition in Japan and Germany"
  - Draft-Neigher Global Nor Standard, Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
    From file box labeled: Wal-Mart (boxed 1/07)--Draft of a paper comparing Wal-Mart and IKEA, written with Nathan Lillie
  - Can Walmartization Be Stopped, 2003-03 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    From file box labeled: Wal-Mart (boxed 1/07)--June 2003 version of a paper/talk originally completed in September, 2001, to be presented at Laboratorio de Anlisis Institucional del Sistema Universitario Mexicano Universidad Autnoma Metropolitana (lecture noted here: http://laisumedu.org/DESIN_Ibarra/salon/Walmartizacion.htm; paper on-line at http://laisumedu.org/DESIN_Ibarra/salon/si2/wm-29.pdf).
  - Wal-Mart Paper, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    From file box labeled: Wal-Mart (boxed 1/07)--Notes relating to the Wal-Mart paper she was writing, as well as thoughts on others' work and a couple of short notes from Neil Wrigley.
  - Wal-Mart Draft 03/04 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    From file box labeled: Wal-Mart (boxed 1/07)--Material related to the paper for Stan Brunn's edited book
  - Wal-Mart Revisions, Undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    From file box labeled: Wal-Mart (boxed 1/07)--Notes relating to the Wal-Mart paper she was writing
  - Rural NY Economy (Box 5, Folder 11)
    A couple of articles about rural economies plus the appendix to a report (draft) by Arch Dotson, Bob Roe, and SMC (dated 1/19/00) entitled "The Danby Economy"
  - UNCTAD Conference, 2000-2002-11-15 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Materials relating to a UN Conference on Trade and Development meeting at which SMC presented--includes a report entitled "Jordan's Policies and Strategies in Audiovisual Media' that is dated April 30, 2000, written by SMC
  - Creative Economy Upstate, Undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Includes a set of notes plus two newsletters
  - Creative Class Articles, Undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - For Sloan Proposal, Undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Contains proposals for British research projects and an article (with SMC comments) she was asked to review for Economic Geography
  - Barnett Symposium, 2003-03-2003-04-01 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Invitation and materials related to a conference on the future viability of the arts at Ohio State
  - ACSP November 21-24,2002 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    Materials relating to a presentation at the Association of Collegiate Schools of Planning meetings in 2002, including paper and transparencies for a paper entitled "School Finance and Income Inequality - Lessons from New York State," on which SMC is first author and Remington Stone is second.
  - PPIC Presentation, Undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Contains transparencies and 6-page handwritten outline of a talk "Are Quality and Equality Incompatible? The Foundations of Continued Inequality in California School Finance" given at the Public Policy Institute of California. Also contains manuscript for a book review of Dreier, et al.'s book, 'Place Matters.'
  - Send Report-Photonics, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Cultural Economy Contacts, Undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
    Includes various materials related to cultural economy approach, notably a program and notes (both for her talk and about others' talks) from the Art, Culture and the Changing Economy a 2002 conference at which SMC appeared on a panel with Richard Florida
  - Re-Thinking Rural Economic Development: A Creative Economy Model-proposal draft (Box 5, Folder 21)
    Proposal for a USDA grant submitted with Suzanne Loker (Textiles and Apparel) and Ben Wood (Education) as co-Pis
  - Hatch Proposal 06/30/2003, 2002-2003 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    Contains material related to the Re-Thinking Rural Economic Development grant proposal, including final draft and letter from the Cornell University Agricultural Experiment Station saying that the preproposal has been selected as one to move forward to USDA, pending submittal of a completed draft.
  - Munich Conference, 2003-2004-03-13 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    Contains material related to a symposium--Create Laboour in New Cultural Economies, organized by Angela McRobbie--includes notes for SMC presentation
  - Lit: Creative Economy Projects, Undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
    Lots of notes and a few papers related to creative economy projects
  - Festival Draft, Undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
    Handwritten notes for a paper on festival tourism, the paper: 'Building the Creative Economy in New York: The Community Festival Option," and related notes and materials
  - Dowd, Timothy, Undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
    An article by Down and Dobbin annotated, and two pages of hand-written notes
  - Rutherford, Tod D., Undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
    Typescripts of articles by Tod Rutherford, annotated with SMC notes
  - Pike, Andy, 2006-04-13 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    E-mail from Andy Pike to participants in the AAG panels (including SMC), 'Whither Regional Studies,' about the special issues they want to pull together from the sessions.
  - Lagendijk, Dr. Arnoud, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    Lagendijk's 2006 AAG paper with two pages of handwritten notes
  - Creative Industries materials, Undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
    Contains 2-page handout "The Crative Industries in Ithaca, New York, some clippings, and notes from a meeting
  - Losing Ground Follow-up, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    Contains SMC and Pendall Brookings report, 'Losing Ground,' and memo entitled "Possible questions re: Losing Ground," which seems to address some possible questions reporters might raise in interviews
  - Creative Economy Docs, Undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
    Contains a variety of materials relating to creative economy project including a book tied to a 2003 UNESCO conference, The International Creative Sector, at the University of Texas at Austin.
  - Hatch Project Data, etc., 2003-2005 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    Survey results, report to funders, IRB application and other materials relating to the Hatch Project--a.k.a. Re-Thinking Rural Economic Development: A Creative Economy Model
    - Hatch Project Press Release, Undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
      A press release of the survey results of conducted by Susan Monagan as part of the project
    - Meeting, May 3rd, 2004-2005-05-03 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Invitations, talk, comments by Syracuse University President, Nancy Cantor, that draw on the SMC project, etc.
    - Creative Economies Strategies QCME Workshop, 2004-04-09 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      Draft paper--Creative Economy Strategies for Small and Medium Size Cities: Options for New York State prepared for the Quality Communities Marketing and Economics Workship, Albany, April 20, 2004
    - Survey Results/ Monagan, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      Typescript of survey conducted by Susan Monagan
    - Final CC Presidents Presentation, Undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
      Printout of slides with SMC notes for talk--entitled Creative Alliances: How Community Colleges Contribute to the Creative Economy
    - College CE Study/Survey Results, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      Contains responses to survey of colleges along with an overview of best practices (and a draft of the same) and an abstract of the findings.
    - Empire State Poll Results, 2004-05-11 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      Complete Survey Research Institute report of results of the Empire State Poll 2004 Cultural Activities Omnibus commissioned by SMC and Suzanne Loker
    - Cornell and Economic Development Project, 2004-07-20 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      An e-mail chain regarding Warren Brown getting directors of the NYS Economic Development Districts prgrams interested in SMC work on clusters
    - University EconDev Centers, 2004-2005 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      Notes and correspondence relating to monies that might be available from the Economic and Development Adminstration of the U.S. Department of Commerce
    - Rockefeller/NYFI Proposal, 2004-08-24 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      A letter to Katherine McFate at the Rockefeller Foundation in response to a note that seemingly asks SMC if she would like support for her project
    - Text for CRA 635 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      Materials relating to the CRP 635 Workshop on State Economic Development Practices--contains a short piece by SMC on clusters and economic development
    - Brookings, Spring 2005 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      Materials tied to project with Rolf Pendall on demographic and econoic changes in Upstate NY, includes reports for Brookings, slides from a talk by SMC and RP, coverage in a CRP publication. Worth noting at the end of the slides is the summary of publicity the project has received.
    - NYCity Media Study Chron File, 2004-08-16-2004-09-18 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      Contains Sponsored Programs Internal Academic Approval form and note to Holly Ladue regarding a study that used no sources and made questionable claims
    - NYC Media Study Materials, Undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
      Contains various source material for project w/some annotations etc.
    - Runaway Production, 2003-2004 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      Folder with charts, a letter from Mike Asher who is editing a book (Contracting Out Hollywood) in which SMC has a chapter, and related materials
    - Canadian Media, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      Stories about Canadian media industries
    - Divide and Conquor notes, 2003-06 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      Notes and a draft of 'Divide and Conquor,' the essay that would be published in 'Contracting Out Hollywood.'
    - Media Materials, Undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
      Materials related to the study of Hollywood and the film industry, including handwritten notes that say "USE for Media Book," although it is unclear if they are for the Divide and Conquor essay or for her own, unpublished, media book.
    - Food worker study materials, Undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
      Draft of biographical data, project schedule, etc. from a proposal for research on, I believe, food workers with Ned Rightor. Linda Nessel's bio is crossed out from one draft.
    - Deliberative Democracy, Undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
      Notes entitled "Deliberative Democracy for Intro," related to Hydraulic Fracturing Project
    - Berlin 7-5, 2015 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      Notes and edited slide print outs and related materials for a talk on hydraulic fracturing
    - Rush to Drill Book/CLIO, 2014 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      Materials and notes relating to a draft book chapter for a project on hydraulic fracturing involving Madelon Finkel
    - International Gas Drilling, Undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
      Materials and notes
    - DEC Hudson Survey, 2014 (Box 6, Folder 23)
      Materials relating to a survey of communities along the Hudson River Line about crude oil transport
    - Law Hydro-Frack, Undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Gas Econ Impact, Undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
      Contains materials and notes including notes for talk called "For presentation to nature society" and one called "Notes for WSKG Presentation" as well as a paper written with Ned Rightor ('How Should We Think About the Economic Consequences of Shale Gas Drilling?'), edited slides for a talk (title unknown), and related materials.
    - Preface, 2015-02-05 (Box 6, Folder 26)
      Newspaper with photo of anti-drilling protesters in Pennsylvania
    - Crude Oil Transport, 2014-2015 (Box 6, Folder 27)
      Report on crude oil transport from Congress along with SMC note regarding JPER articles
    - Introduction, Undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
      Notes toward an introduction to a book(?) on hydraulic fracturing some handwritten, some typed
    - NIMBY, Undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
      Articles relating to gas-related NIMBYism (Not in my back yard-ism)
    - Marcellus Gas Drilling Interviews, Undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
      Notes relating to interview plan and related articles
    - Arrests-Research Results, 2012-07-02 (Box 6, Folder 31)
      Annotated report entitled "Preliminary Report on Arrest/Offense Data and Drilling Activity in Major US Shale Play
    - Community Responses Study, 2012 (Box 6, Folder 32)
      Contains results of survey of communities that took legislative action with regard to shale gas drilling as well as student reports to SMC (including one done as a final project)
    - Marcellus Shale ED, Undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
      Notes and other materials
    - Albany Meetings, Undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
      Correpondence and a short piece on Building the Potential for Green Manufacturing in NY
    - Empire State Survey: Notes for Commuity Study, 2012 (Box 6, Folder 35)
      Results from 2012 Empire State Poll on natural gas drilling, notes on how to summarize the results, and a sheet of notes entitled 'Susan Arbetter'
    - Dublin Keynote Address, 2014-11 (Box 6, Folder 36)
      Notes and slides related to a keynote address on rethinking regional clusters given at a conference sponsored by the Higher Education Authority of Ireland, November 26, 2014
    - Lumina Indianapolis Talk Ideas, Undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
      Notes and two syllabi from Nichola Lowe for economic development courses
    - Lumina Conference Refs, Undated (Box 6, Folder 38)
      Articles and an anonymous essay marked "for Lumina review"
    - Bos Ppr Framing (Boston Paper Framing), Undated (Box 6, Folder 39)
      Notes and materials for a presentation in Boston related to the creative economy in small cities, with reference to institutions of higher education
    - Tech Transfer Paper, Undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
      Lots of notes and some related material for a paper on tech transfer
    - Perry Paper Framing, Undated (Box 6, Folder 41)
      Notes and related materials
    - For Perry/OECD Papers, Undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Why Universities Won't Save Us, Undated (Box 6, Folder 43)
      Edited draft of a paper entitled "Why Universities Won't Save Us: The Limits to "the Learning Region" as a Formula for Sustainable Regional Economies" and related materials
    - Energy Transitions Clippings (Box 6, Folder 44)
      Assorted clippings related to energy transitions, some with notes
    - Energy Transitions Notes, Undated (Box 6, Folder 45)
      Four pages of notes on a range of topics, one headed "Question to answer: What does state-centric network mean for energy transitions? Movement from one form to another or lock in?"